https://hagermanart.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
William "Byron" Hagerman-Artist
Realistic and Impressionist Oil Paintings | Two Styles, Two Signatures, One Artist
Privacy Policy
Who we areThis is the website blog for artist William Hagerman whose primary website is: https://www.hagermanart.comOur website address for this blog is: https://hagermanart.com/blog and is powered by WordPress.I am located in the United States of America.What personal data I collect and why I collect it.Not all data mentioned below may be in use depending on which services are currently active.Basically private information is what you share when you purchase an item or service and is used to fulfill that order or when you voluntarily supply when commenting on my blog, signing up for my newsletter or when sending an email or using my contact form.CommentsWhen visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.Source: Akismet Anti-Spam PluginWe collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.MediaIf you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website. (Uploading images from visitors is not allowed on this site, however some photos may be sent via regular email during support sessions in my online art classes.)Source: Photo Gallery PluginYour name, email address and IP address are collected and stored in our website database when you comment on and/or rate images on our website.Contact forms and EmailWhenever you use my contact form your name and email address is collected along with information you personally provide. Your information is used to respond to your request or inquiry and fulfill any services or transactions and is kept for as long as necessary to fulfill your request. Your information is not used to send you marketing emails or newsletters, unless you specifically give consent, such as when signing up for my newsletter or opting in on my contact form.Source: Easy Digital Downloads (eBook purchases) or other online purchases including Online Art ClassesWe collect information about you during the checkout process on our store. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and any other details that might be requested from you for the purpose of processing your orders.Handling this data also allows us to:– Send you important account/order/service information.– Respond to your queries, refund requests, or complaints.– Process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.– Set up and administer your account, provide technical and/or customer support, and to verify your identity.Additionally we may also collect the following information:– Location and traffic data (including IP address and browser type) if you place an order, or if we need to estimate taxes and shipping costs based on your location.– Product pages visited and content viewed while your session is active.– Your comments and product reviews if you choose to leave them on our website.– Account email/password to allow you to access your account, if you have one.– If you choose to create an account or membership with us, your name, address, and email address, depending on the service which will be used to administer your account or membership for video art classes or possibly populate the checkout for future orders or class subscriptions if available in the future.CookiesThis section contains information on the use of cookies as a visitor and any with a member account.If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.All cookies can be managed in your browser to accept or not to accept them with the understanding some functionality may be limited or not work.Embedded content from other websitesArticles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.AnalyticsLog DataFor each visitor to Hagerman Art, and in common with other websites, our web server automatically collects statistical data, none of which personally identifies you. It does not collect your name or email address. This data is occasionally reviewed and analyzed to check the performance of this website and is used to improve this website for all visitors. Whenever you visit this website information that your browser sends to us is called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser version, pages visited on my site and the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, and other statistics. It is not used to attempt to find out your location or market to you.Who we share your data withInformation about my customers is important to my business and developing a relationship with my customers based on trust. I share your personal information for very limited reasons and in limited circumstances, as follows:* Service providers. I engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services, such as delivery companies when shipping art work. I will share your personal information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these services.* Compliance with laws. I may collect, use, retain, and share your information if I have a good faith belief that it is reasonably necessary to: (a) respond to legal process or to government requests; (b) enforce my agreements, terms and policies; (c) prevent, investigate, and address fraud and other illegal activity, security, or technical issues; or (d) protect the rights, property, and safety of my customers, or others.* I do not share or sell your information to third parties for the purpose of marketing.How long we retain your dataIf you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.What rights you have over your dataIf you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.Where we send your dataVisitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.Your contact informationYou may contact me using my email form or directly.Additional informationHow we protect your dataI value your trust in providing any Personal Information that you provide, and please keep in mind you’re dealing with a sole individual and not a large corporation that has the resources to implement extensive safeguards. Remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security. Safeguards are in place that protects sensitive information such as credit card information when you make a purchase on this site. PayPal is used as the payment processor. For those who do make a purchase via PayPal you will be bound by their Privacy Policy and safeguards as you are using their services. If more stringent data protection is a concern to you, or you live in the EU or country that requires more safeguards than what is stated hear, please don’t interact with this website or blog.For each visitor to Hagerman Art, and in common with other websites, our web server automatically collects statistical data, including but not limited to a visitor’s IP address, browser type, operating system, time of visit, and referring pages, none of which personally identifies you. It does not collect your email address. This data is occasionally reviewed and analyzed to check the performance of this website and is used to improve this website for all visitors.Personally identifiable information is collected only when you provide it, such as when filling out a form, making a purchase including online video classes.  This information may be used in one or more of the following ways.To respond to an inquiry or request for information. To process transactions.To send you periodic emails.To enhance this website based on information and feedback received from you.Your information will not be sold, exchanged or transferred to any other company or business, other than for the sole purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested by you and to complete the transaction.The email address you provide when contacting Hagerman Art, the artist William Hagerman or the email address provided for order processing, may be used to contact you to reply to your requests, or to send you updates concerning your order, to inform you of new products, services and events from Hagerman Art or from the artist William Hagerman. You may opt-out from receiving emails by following the instructions provided with each email. In lieu of the foregoing, personally identifiable information may be shared with governmental agencies or other companies assisting with fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when permitted or required by law. Attempting to protect or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions. Investigating fraud which has already taken place. This information is not provided to these companies for the purpose of marketing.When making a purchase I use PayPal to process transactions. When making a purchase, you may review the PayPal Privacy Policy via the link provided on the shopping cart or payment page regarding how they use the information you provide.This privacy policy may be updated at anytime and changes will be posted on this page.Should you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding this privacy policy, please contact us.William Hagerman
Site Navigation
Menu
Home
Art Work
Available Paintings
Portfolio
Commissioned Artwork
Art Shows
Contact
PO Box 1316Winnsboro, TX 75494william@hagermanart.com(432) 638-2584 see call timesCall: Mon – Fri: 9 am – 5 pm CSTSaturday: 1 pm – 5 pm CST
Galleries
Folger GallerySherwoods Gallery
Keep in Touch
Click here for my sign up form!I invite you to to sign up to receive periodic updates and newsletters in your in-box! I don’t share your email address or overload you with emails.
HagermanArt.com © 2020| All Rights Reserved | Privacy Policy
